Mohammad El Prince

Milton, ON | 519-760-1559 | mohammad-elprince@proton.me <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Full Stack Software Engineer with experience in JavaScript and Python-based programming. With a background in mechanical engineering and operations, I have a can-do attitude and bring strong skills in problem-solving, communication, and collaboration. I have a clear vision for leveraging technology to solve complex challenges and create meaningful impact. As a lifelong learner, I am committed to growing my technical knowledge and leadership skills. I enjoy tackling challenges head-on and crafting creative solutions to real-world problems. My belief in the power of teamwork through the Agile methodology guides me in achieving exceptional results.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, React.js, Next.js, FastAPI, Scss, SQL, VSCode, Git

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

WriteWell - GitHub | Demo | Live

WriteWell is a full-stack app that enables bloggers to share, edit, and delete blogs.

- Built with Next.js end-to-end and styled with Scss.
- Employed Next. is routing ability to construct endpoints for API requests.
- Utilized MySQL as the database, which is deployed on AWS RDS.
- Deployed images to AWS S3 and linked them to the database.

Portfolio - GitHub | Demo | Live

A high-quality digital showcase of my professional journey, highlighting my skills and projects.

- Employed HTML, CSS, and JavaScript showcasing my abilities to learn and in front-end web development and design.
- Incorporated interactive elements and animation using JS and CSS.
- Maintained DRY coding following best practices in all the project files.

GPT-3 Intro - GitHub | Demo | Live

A landing page created to describe GPT-3 technology that provides a brief introduction about this modern AI technology.

- Built with ReactJS and CSS styling showcasing an appealing user experience.
- Incorporated BEM (Block Element Modifier) technique to relate JSX elements to styling and for consistency.
- Deployed JSON server as the backend server.

Budget Tracker CLI - GitHub | Demo

A command-line application designed to help you manage your finances and track your expenses easily.

- Coded python scripts and functions and maintained DRY coding.
- Imported SQLAlchemy for database management.
- Implemented the rich library for a user-friendly CL interface.

FDUCATION

EDUCATION	
Flatiron School Full Stack Web Development, Python and JavaScript online program	02/2023 - 10/2023
University of Guelph, Guelph, ON Master of Engineering — Mechanical Engineering (course-based)	01/2019 – 02/2021
King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals, Dhahran, KSA Master of Science — Mechanical Engineering (Thesis-based) - Computational Fluid Dynamics Bachelor of Science — Mechanical Engineering (course-based)	09/2016 – 12/2018 01/2012 – 05/2016

RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Amazon, Mississauga, ON

05/2021 - Present

Lead Fulfillment Associate/Field Quality Assurance

- Manage 50+ Associates across Amazon Robotics (AR) floor and inventory workstations.
- Monitor the health of four Amazon Robotics floors for optimal productivity and safe operation.
- Guide Associate for an optimized performance resulting in 10% improvement in the AR floor health.
- Train Level1 Leads and provide coverage for other managers of operation.
- Identify barriers to first-time delivery success; recommend improvements to Amazon's systems and processes.
- Interact with property managers regarding deliveries and address concerns with service levels being provided.

University of Guelph, Guelph, ON Research/Teaching Assistant

01/2019 - 05/2021

- Lectured large groups of students (75 150 students) on fundamental engineering courses and proctored exams.
- Conducted experimental and theoretical research in the area of safety of nuclear power plants.
- Provided coverage for professors in lectures.
- Designed assessments and graded students' reports, video reports, assignments, exams, and classroom activities.

King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals, Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

09/2016 - 12/2018

- Teaching/Research Assistant
- Authored two scientific journal papers developing novel studies that improved studies of other authors.
- Developed a computational study that improved the prediction of the gas well lifetime partnering with Saudi Aramco.
- Provided coverage for professors in lectures.
- Graded students' reports, assignments, exams, and classroom activities.
- Lectured fundamental mechanical engineering labs and courses over the course of 5 semesters.